Kelvin Tam

Aerospace Engineering Graduate

k1tam@ryerson.ca • (647) 704-3294 | Canadian Citizen • Toronto, Ontario

Profile Summary

Engineering graduate with documented experience in aerospace machine learning & computer science research, repair mechanics and customer service. I am constantly striving to build my skills & knowledge in the fields of computer science & aviation technology. I am a highly self-motivated and analytical team player with academic and workforce project leadership experience.

Technical Qualifications

Language Fluency: English, Cantonese

Programming: C, C++, JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS, Oracle/MySQL, Machine Learning

Software Proficiency: CATIA V5, Matlab/Simulink, Xfoil, XFLR5, ANSYS, Solidworks, Microsoft Suite, LaTeX

Manufacturing: 3D Printing, Laser Cutting, Electronics/PCB Soldering

Education

Computer Programming & Analysis Advanced Diploma | Seneca College 2022

• Seneca Digital Health Hackathon 2021 - Second Place

B.Eng | Bachelor of Aerospace Engineering | Ryerson University 2019

- Ryerson Aerospace Aircraft Design Capstone Competition 1st Place
- CASI Toronto Aircraft Design, Aircraft Stability & Controls Certificate
- Ryerson Rocketry Club Engineering Team

Work Experience

Research Assistant June 2020 - July 2021

Ryerson University (Toronto, ON)

- Assisted in the development of an automated 3D printing quality control system for aerospace manufacturing purposes with different printing materials, climate control, infill strength & percentages
- Using Python, JavaScript, Deep Machine Learning Algorithms & multiple visual sensors, a scaled system is created to
 detect, catalogue manufactured product defects and identify new printing anomalies.
- The created system yielded a 98% detection success rate, increasing the manufacturing process reliability and reducing net waste from defective units & printing material

Bicycle Sales Associate & Repair Mechanic

May 2018 - June 2020

Switchback Cyclery - Social Enterprise (Toronto, ON)

- Client consultation experience in custom builds & upgrades, with thorough understanding of component level integration, future maintainability & upgradability based on technical guidelines/schematics
- Responsible for developing/presenting (at high level) & completing technical service orders & solutions with component listings in consideration of clients' necessities, safety, budgets, and desired performance level
- Consistent client communication on service order updates & critical findings to provide full service transparency

Bakery Chef & Brand Ambassador (Hershey's Kitchen - 2 month)

November 2019 - January 2020

Mosaic Sales Solution (Toronto, ON)

- Prepared made-to-order specialty items with a team of 5 while maintaining rigorous quality control in a fast-paced boutique kitchen pop-up
- Reported and maintained daily baked goods inventory, raw material & shop necessities to managing supervisors

Hillsong Church Toronto (Toronto, ON)

- Led a team of three in stage lighting setup/routing & live hardware operations in various venues across Toronto
- Responsible for developing seasonal stage lighting design elements, LX show files programming, venue hardware route mapping and annual equipment upgrades, cost estimates & budget proposals
- Served as design approval contact, roster/project management and technical training for new systems & guidelines

Supervisor - Barista

May 2016 - December 2017

Starbucks (Toronto, ON)

- Strengthened the corporate image by providing personalized experiences through Barista services
- Effectively managed store hours by allocating available work hours for employees and boosted daily sales targets

Project Experience

Project Manager, Aerodynamics & Structures, 3D Modeler

Aircraft Design Capstone - Electric Single-Prop Trainer Aircraft (team of 12 members)

- Utilized **CATIA V5** with advanced techniques to produce accurate modeling of aircraft systems with professionally scaled engineering drawings at component & assembly level
- Designed a hybrid airfoil with 30% higher efficiency than similar class in-market products, optimized with XFLR5 &
 ANSYS Computational Fluid Dynamics and estimated wing capabilities using Boolean Subtraction Method
- Guiding system integration and progress updates/deliverables while being in close liaison with subteams and faculty
- Analyzed wing and fuselage skeleton components' structural integrity, stress allowance and deformation failures, using ANSYS Finite Element Analysis, to refine and minimize total aircraft weight while meeting safety constraints

Agricultural Drone Design Project

Technical Involvement - Structural Design & Analysis

- Developed an Arduino based agricultural purposed drone sensor package which monitors crop conditions, detects for fresh crop locations and maximum sizing. Compatible with a wide angle camera module package
- Using CATIA V5, a drone mountable protective enclosure was produced & 3D printed with specific payload weight & dimensional requirements
- Structural integrity of the payload enclosure was tested using ANSYS stress analysis on various impact possibilities & simulation of mission loads before live prototype trials
- Successful implementation of drone sensor package with live usable data feedback under test flight conditions